[music]
>> Hello everybody. This is Gina. Today,
I'm going to show you how to make a very
simple, very quick moving project. We're
going to make a bracelet with the newest
treasure bags, the Desert Dreams
collection.
And I'm going to show you an example
from each bag here. I am going to create
this one during the tutorial.
Let's
And I'm using a little magnetic
fold-over clasp with this, but you can
use whatever clasping you want.
At well, come here. And
slide that through there.
That's what that one looks like. And
then we've got the Starlit Nights bag.
And
these colors just worked out really
great with the large porcelain bead in
the bag.
>> [snorts]
>> Looks really good. So, that's what these
look like.
Really simple, really fast, and just
something you could wear every day. It's
just casual enough or dressy enough
regard
depending upon how you want to
dress up your wardrobe with it.
Anyway, I'm going to stop rambling
because I don't even know what I'm
talking about, and let's look at the
material list. Okay?
Let's do it. Okay, for this project
today, we're going to make a really
cute, very simple bracelet with the
newest treasure bags, the Desert Dreams
collection. So, with the Starlit Nights,
I have made my original design. On this
tutorial today, I will be using the Sun
Swept Sands. They're exactly the same
components, same numbers, everything.
You will just be using the color
selection that you have.
So, what we're going to be using is the
large
porcelain bead that you got in your bag.
You either got this chocolaty glazed one
or you got this gray one.
And then we're going to be using six of
our gemstone beads. This is a 6-mm round
tiger's eye. These are 6-mm round
howlite.
So, you'll use whichever one you want or
you can use any 6-mm bead that you feel
like you would like to do. Then we're
going to be using
about
six of these little
metal beads that came in your bag.
I'm going to add to the bag two bead
caps. I do have some of these on my
website if you want some. Otherwise,
just use something that works well.
And then we are going to add two
crimp tubes. These are size two
beadalon.
And then I'm going to use some Toho seed
beads and these are in 80 and they are
nickel.
You're going to need some medium
Soft Flex stringing wire or you can use
anything comparable. This is what I'm
using today and I have cut about 10 and
1/2 in of it.
I'm also adding to this
a new clasp that I got online. These are
little magnetic clasps. I actually have
the fold over part
on here wrong. So, it's a fold over
clasp. It's magnetic. It just pops
together like that.
And
it will
hook around
this little textured guy. He's textured
on one side, so you want to make sure
that you actually put the textured side
up.
And this is what this looks like. Now,
you can use the clasping in your bag or
any clasping that you would like. You do
not have to get one of these. It's just
that before my wrist was broken, I
ordered a bunch of different clasps and
I never had a chance to sit down and see
if they worked or play with them or do
tutorials with them simply because of
the fact that I couldn't move my
fingers. So,
um I'm
with this bag, I'm kind of messing with
them so that I can get them up, and I
like to try them out first to make sure
how they work and if they work well.
So, that's what I'm doing. So, let's go
ahead and get started with this project.
Okay, so we're going to start this
project by attaching the clasp to one
end of our wire.
So, and like I said, I cut about 10 and
1/2 in of wire.
Maybe 11, right around there.
And I'm just going to open up my
magnetic clasp, take off this end so
it's not so bulky, and I'm going to
attach this end onto my wire. So, I'm
going to pick up a size two crimp tube
onto my wire,
drop it down a little ways, and then I'm
going to pick up my clasp,
and let me get you a little closer,
and I'm going to put it through this
little loop on the end here.
And then I'm just going to pull some
wire through,
go back through
this crimp tube.
I'm just going to push about I don't
know, not quite a quarter of an inch
through,
and then I am going to hold onto that
crimp tube and pull the longer strand so
that I retain most of my
beading wire to bead with, and I don't
have it
sticking out that I have to cut off.
So, then you want to arrange it to where
you have a nice little loop around your
clasp so it will move. Not huge, not
tiny.
Then arrange your wires inside so that
they are not crossed
like this. So, they're laying next to
each other, they're parallel inside this
crimp tube. Then, I'm going to grab my
crimping tool, and I'm going to place it
in the second divot closest to the
handle, and I'm going to squeeze.
And now, I have
a little division in the middle of the
crimp tube, tubes [snorts] on either
side,
and then I'm going to place those in
sideways so the little tubes are
touching the crimp tube in the first
divot closest to the tip of the tool,
and squeeze again.
That will draw those two tubes together
tightly, and you'll get a nice secure
crimp.
Now, we have one end of our wire
prepared. I'm going to grab my flush
cutters,
and I'm going to just wrap the longer
piece of beading wire over my finger,
and that will make this one pop up, and
I'm just going to cut it as close to
that crimp tube as I can, maybe leaving
just a little bit sticking out.
Then, I'm going to grab an 8/0 seed
bead, and Toho's will pop right over
that end, so you won't have anything
sharp or pokey sticking out. So, just
bring that all the way down.
Then, we're going to start our sequence
of beading, so I'm going to pick up the
flat little silver square beads, and I
am an 8/0, and then that bead, and then
an 8/0,
and a gemstone,
or anything 6 mm round, that's fine. And
then, an 8/0,
and then
another of our square beads, and that is
our pattern.
This is going to make about a 7 and 1/2
in bracelet with this particular style
of clasping. Now, you may have to adjust
according to your
um the size of your clasp, how many
beads you put on here.
So, I've got my pattern established
here.
Another 8/0.
Another of my
square beads, another 8/0.
And another gemstone
and 8/0.
Then, I'm going to grab a little bead
cap because this covers the end of the
big porcelain bead really nicely. Gives
it a better finish. You can use whatever
you have on hand that wraps around it
nicely. And um if you have one that
comes over it more, you will not have to
um put some seed beads inside to balance
it, which I'm going to show you in a
minute. But,
>> [snorts]
>> I'm going to use this little four petal
and drop it down. And then, in order to
balance this,
I'm going to put some 8/0 seed beads
inside it. Now, this one, the 8/0's
lodged right on the end, which is
perfect. I could just when I I had
strung it on here just to mess with it,
they stuck in there and it was perfect.
I didn't have to fill this
bead up with any other beads because it
lodged in there perfect. However, these
beads are handmade and the ends are
different on every one. Some of them
aren't quite as round. It won't
accommodate the 8/0's. Some of them are
bigger and the 8/0's fall in. So, what
I'm going to do with this one
is I'm going to put an 8/0 on here
and I'm going to see what happens.
If this slides over the top of it, if it
doesn't, you can use an auger like this
and you can just gently
auger the ends a little bit, too,
to make it slide over the 8/0.
If it won't at all, then use 11/0 seed
beads for this and fill it up
completely, the bead up. But, I'm just
going to see if I can get this to stick
on the end. And the problem with this
one is it's a big hole and the 8/0's are
falling in. So, I'm going to pick up
more 8/0's instead of just one to lodge
it there. I'm going to pick up
Now, I've got three. So, there's four,
five, six, seven, eight. Nine.
10.
And both sides don't always
work the same, either. So, I'm going to
see if these will slide in here.
And you see, this side, they won't slide
down. So, what I can do, let's see if
it's going to slide in there.
So, what I can do is I can just lodge
this side.
And just keep that bead right there. Or,
I can take my auger
take this off and I'm going to just make
it a little bit bigger so that it will
lodge right in the edge of this.
Like this one did.
You just have to mess with this part,
like I said, because these beads and you
don't have to put anything at all. But,
it does hold the bead cap in the right
place if you do this. And it does hold
your bead from sliding all over the
place because it's got a big hole. And
also, some of your 8/0's are bigger than
others. So, if you can find one that
just lodges right in there,
then that's perfect. And then, you just
put another bead cap on.
Let's see how that looks. And that looks
just fine. See?
And this one that I made, they lodged
right in the edge and I only had to put
one on
either side.
Then
I am going to pick up another 80 seed
bead.
And I will repeat my pattern on this
side. So, I'll pick up a gemstone.
And then an 80.
One of my little square beads.
80.
Gemstone.
Oh, come here, you little
dude. There we go.
And then another of my square beads.
And
an 80 gemstone 80.
Square bead.
And then an 80.
Then I am going to grab a crimp tube
and slide it down.
Just like that.
Then I need to find the other end of my
clasping. I want this
since I have this side of the clasping
down towards my bead mat, I'm going to
make sure that the textured side of this
is down towards my bead mat, also.
So, that they will the outsides of them
will
connect and look correct on your wrist.
Then, we're going to slide
>> [clears throat]
>> our round part of our clasp down.
We're going to go into the crimp tube.
And into I'm going to go ahead and go
through the 80 and the
flat bead here. If I can get through.
Just like that. Oops, I got another 80.
I don't want you. You get off of there.
Just like that.
So, you can see
what I've got.
Just like this.
Now, I have my clasp down here. I'm
going to hold on to I'm going to push
crimp tube down a little bit and hold on
to it. Just keep scooting it all down.
Then, once they're the beads are
touching, I'm going to hold on to the
stable side of my loop because one side
will move and one side is stable. So,
then I'm going to pull this down
until I can't really hold on to that
loop anymore. Then, I'll hold on to
several of the beads. Pull this down as
tight as I can.
Arrange this so that it's in the proper
position, and I am not leaving any um
slack in that loop. I'm doing it as
tight as I can.
And then, what I will do, and you can
only do this if if your beads are tight
on your bead stringing wire. So, using
medium holds this for you. If you're
using a smaller
um beading wire, and it doesn't hold
everything really tight, you can't do
this method. You're just going to have
to cut it off after you crimp. But, I'm
going to cut this before I crimp because
it has certain benefits in doing so. So,
I can go right underneath
this bead here.
And the benefit now is, since this is
squished up really tight, my loop
doesn't have any slack. I can now take
that little
crimp tube and push it down
and give myself some room for a loop.
What this does is it draws that little
end that you put through your bead up
into the bead, positions it there, holds
it there, and then you won't have any
space between your beads because of that
little wire, and you won't have a pokey.
It hides it perfectly. Now, I'm going to
make sure this moves, and it does. Hold
on to it carefully because it is not
secure because we did not crimp yet.
Then, we're going to place this into our
crimping tool in the second divot
closest to the handle, and we're going
to squeeze.
And now I have the first half of my
crimp just like this. Now, I'm going to
place that inside ways just like I
showed you before, and squeeze again.
Make sure you do not squeeze that bead
here cuz it's a glass bead, and you're
going to shatter it. So,
then
we can put this together.
Open this up.
And we have a cute little bracelet.
Now, I'm going to go ahead and slide
this on my wrist and show it to you. I'm
going to show you both of these here.
Um
this one turned out really cute, too. I
really like the how light and the gray
bead that looks really nice together.
This one looks really nice together.
They turned out really nice. So, um
let's measure it so that you can know
exactly how big this is. And again, this
is contingent upon your clasping, too.
So, I'm going to take this off. This
takes up a pretty good space, this
clasping. So, you may have to do more if
you have a different style of clasp.
So, I'm going to measure it from where
the round
portion slides in
to the magnetic portion, and then
about halfway through the loop here
because that's how it will position
itself. So, it's about a 7
in bracelet. So, that lets you know how
big it is. Also, you have to realize
that you're going to need about a
quarter of an inch more than you usually
do. So, I can wear a 7-in but I like
mine to have a little bit of movement
and a 7-1/2
um allows for the room for this little
bead cuz it's
it's got um
some width to it.
And
with this one, I could have probably put
a few more beads inside there. And see
how what I mean about the
the little bead caps moving around. On
this one, it did not because I was able
to get them a little closer. So, you
just kind of have to finagle it. It
looks fine regardless. I will put it on
and show you that it looks good. And
we'll be back in a moment. Okay, so I
have put them both on. I was thinking
off camera, too. You could conceivably
glue a bead cap on either side of the
bead, too. But there again, if you just
fill it up with a bunch of
8/0s or 11/0s, you don't even have to
put a bead cap on it. Then just play
with it, get creative with it, and
figure out what look you want to
achieve. It looks fine the way it is.
But um if that really bothers you that
the bead cap isn't perfect, then you can
glue it on first. I just make such a
mess with glue.
So, if you were to do that, I would make
sure that I put something through
the bead cap and the bead so that you
don't fill it up with glue.
And then glue it on there just on the
edges and let it set up and then you can
string it right on. Um that would work
fine, too. But I think this is just fine
and I don't have a problem with the way
any of it looks and I will wear this
just
perfectly fine. But these are what these
look like and this is what the clasping
looks like. Turned out really cute,
really simple, really fast. And um
I'll put some links for these if you
want them. If not, like I said, just use
what you got. And let's take this off.
And take a peek at them again.
And
there you have it.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and
we'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye.
>> [music]
[music]